Contact

karapiper005@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kara-westurn-a15b87166 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare
Hospitals
Healthcare Management

Kara Westurn

Corrections Regional Director|Dialysis|Registered Nurse Mercersburg, Pennsylvania

Summary

Dedicated Operations Leader with years of expertise in healthcare organizations and medical practices, optimizing all processes and enhancing results. Facilitated the execution of plans against target deadlines and business objectives and applied both project and change management best practices. Identified opportunities to increase efficiency and improve quality, quantify impact, prioritize initiatives, and develop execution plans.

Experience

CharDonnay Dialysis | CDI Health Corrections Regional Director June 2020 - Present (2 months)

Spring Creek Nursing and Rehab Manager Dialysis and Respiratory April 2020 - June 2020 (3 months)

In my position with Spring Creek Nursing and Rehabilitation Center, I expertly supervised a high acuity unit. I cooperated with interdisciplinary teams to ensure best care practices. I held responsibility for meeting quality measures and employee engagement.

Dialysis Care Center Area Manager February 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 3 months)

As an Area Manager, I partnered with local and corporate hospital administrators to guarantee the growth of all modalities, including CKD education, Incenter, Home, Inpatient, and Home Assist. I generated innovative ideas and strategies to exceed goals, objectives, and strategic plans. I communicated with the CEO on budget development, performance management, and best practices to align with company guidelines. I recruited top-tier professionals and completed disciplinary actions in collaboration with

the HR department. I established solid management for numerous locations and modalities in all clinics.

The following are highlights of the value I have brought to the company:

- Launched three new Denovo clinics having acquired Deficiency Free State Certification.
- Successfully expanded services to include Home Therapy Programs.
- Instrumental as a liaison managing communications between Medical Directors, CEOs, Presidents, physicians, and Medical Advisory Board members.

Fresenius Medical Care North America
Program Manager
December 2013 - February 2019 (5 years 3 months)

During my time with Fresenius Kidney Care, I presided as a Program Manager overseeing five acute-care level hospital dialysis centers. I maintained quality patient care through adherence with the company's mission and values. I organized Quality Improvement Activities (QIA's) in an effort to identify areas for improvement in performance. I fostered relationships with hospital administrators and contractors. I oversaw medical supply inventory, accounts payable, and personnel regarding cost analysis. I collaborated with the Director of Operations to enhance the financial status of each center.

The following are highlights of the value I have brought to the company:

- Secured a 95% staff retention rate in a difficult position.
- Successfully repaired strained affiliate relationships.

EXPERIENCE, CONT.

Summit Health
Registered Nurse
June 2013 - November 2013 (6 months)

In my time as a Staff Nurse, I evaluated existing standards of care for efficacy and implemented standards to achieve departmental goals and deliver exemplary patient care. I utilized analytical skills in assessing conditions and implementing appropriate interventions. I served as a liaison between patients

and physicians, certifying patient treatment plans. I collected blood and tissue for lab testing. I educated patients and family members on health maintenance and infant care.

Birth Matters Doula Service
Doula
January 2001 - April 2012 (11 years 4 months)

Summit Health
Childbirth Educator
April 2002 - July 2003 (1 year 4 months)

Schoeneman Beauty Supply
Sales Manager
February 1997 - January 2001 (4 years)

Education

Western Governors University

Master's degree, Leadership and Management · (2019 - 2022)

Penn State University
Registered Nurse · (2011 - 2013)